Personal Information



Name: Omid Aghababaei Jazi, Ph.D.

Address: 686 Bay St. 11th floor, L17 South The Hospital for Sick Children, PGCRL

Toronto, ON, M5G 0A4.

E-mail: omid.jazi@utoronto.ca **Phone Number**: 438-873-4388

About Me

I am currently a postdoctoral fellow at the Hospital for Sick Children, Biostatistics group. My research interests are longitudinal data analysis, survival analysis, and variable selection methods. I also have immense passion for teaching and have 8 years' experience in Statistics courses.

Education						
Ph.D.	Statistics	Fall 2013- M	1ay 2019 McGill University	Montreal, Canada.		
M.Sc.	Statistics	2007-2010	Shahid Beheshti University	Tehran, Iran.		
B.Sc.	Statistics	2003-2007	Isfahan University of Technology	Isfahan, Iran.		

Work Experience

Postdoctoral Fellow July 2019-July 2021 Sickkids Hospital/Biostats Group Toronto, Canada. Researcher/Lecturer 2010-2012 NOET, Faculty of Statistics and Informatics Tehran, Iran.

Awards & Scholarship

- ISM Scholarship for Outstanding PhD Candidates, Montreal, Canada, winter 2018.
- Full Scholarship from the Department of Math and Stats of McGill University for the Ph.D. Program, *Montreal, Canada, 2013-2017. (Schulich, StatLab, NSERC, CRM, GREAT)*
- Highest GPA*, M.Sc. Program in Statistics, Beheshti University, *Tehran, Iran. 2010.*
- First Rank, Individuals and Teams, 8th Iranian Students Statistics Competitions, Iran, 2007.
- Second Rank, 12th National Scientific Olympiad in Statistics, *Iran*, 2007.

Teaching/Mentoring Experience (Material: https://omidaghababaei.github.io/Homepage/)

- Mentoring at the Undergraduate Poster Showcase, McGill University, March 2021.
- **Poster judge during the SickKids Rare Disease Week,** The Hospital for Sick Children, February, 2021.
- Teaching Graduate Course in Mathematical Statistics, McGill University, Fall 2018.
- **Teaching Assistant**, McGill University (Calculus I, II, Probability, Statistics, Principle of Statistics I), Fall 2014-Winter 2019.
- **Teaching Assistant/Lecturer,** Beheshti University/NOET (Calculus, Sampling Methods, Stochastic Processes/ Linear Algebra, Probability, Math Stats), Iran, 2007-2012.

_

^{*(18.47} out of 20)

Recent Training Experience

- Attended SSC Webinar on Teaching Statistics Online, June 2020.
- Taking Mentorship Program at the Hospital for Sick Children, Research Training Center, February-May 2021.
- Attending Training Events for Teaching at Center for Training Support & Innovation (CTSI), University of Toronto, April 2021.
- Attending 14th Annual University of Toronto Teaching and Learning Symposium: Teaching-as-Learner/Learner-as-Teacher, May 2021.

Current Research Projects

- Aghababaei Jazi, O., Pullenayegum, E. Variable Selection in Semiparametric Models for Longitudinal Data with Informative Observation Times.
- Aghababaei Jazi, O., Pullenayegum, E. Predictive Modeling with Longitudinal Data.

Recent Research Projects

- Aghababaei Jazi, O., Asgharian, M., Khalili, A. (2021). *Maximum Composite Profile Likelihood with Right-censored Length-biased Data, to be submitted.*
- Aghababaei Jazi, O., Asgharian, M., Khalili, A. (2021). *Maximum Likelihood Estimation and EM algorithm with Biased Sampling, to be submitted.*
- Aghababaei Jazi, O., Asgharian, M., Khalili, A. (2021). Estimation for Prevalent Cohort Data when the Majority of Observations Is Censored, to be submitted.

Selected Presentations

- Aghababaei Jazi, O. Predictive Modeling of a Multistage Randomized Clinical Trial for Treating Major Depressive Disorder. The Hospital for Sick Children, PDAC, 2021.
- Aghababaei Jazi, O., BUGS Computational Workshop, Dalla Lana School of Public Health, University of Toronto, 2020.
- Aghababaei Jazi, O., MAPLE; Semiparametric Estimation and Variable Selection for Length-biased Data with Heavy Censoring, Department of Math & Stats, McGill University, 2019.

Experience/Skills/Interests

- Data Science Specialization from John Hopkins University.
- Event Lead in Postdoctoral Advisory Committee (PDAC) at Sickkids Hospital.
- Reviewed articles for the Journal of Biometrics and the Canadian Journal of Statistics.
- Interests in playing and watching soccer, cycling, reading, and music.

References

Eleanor Pullenayegum	Masoud Asgharian	Abbas Khalili
University of Toronto	McGill University	McGill University
Eleanor.pullenayegum@sickkids.ca	masoud@math.mcgill.ca	khalili@math.mcgill.ca
416-813-7654 x301031	514-398-1461	514-398-3842